今天的《造物小百科》
Today on How It's Made
钉子和订书钉，每天生产2500万枚
Nails and Staples, 25 million produced every day.
护目镜，从刑侦人员到运动员都在用
Safety glasses, from crime scene investigators to sports.
布料，单个纱线筒就能纺出25公里
Fabrics, 25 kilometers from just a single bobbin.
还有自行车，从碳纤维到轻如羽毛的金属合金
And bicycles, from carbon fiber to feather light metal alloys.
不过首先，正如每位手工行家所说
But first, as every DIY expert will tell you,
笨工匠怪工具，更笨的则怪钉子
a bad workman blames his tools, and an even worse one blames the nail.
这下可没有借口了
Well, now there's no excuse.
无论你用砌筑钉、木钉，平头钉还是沉头钉
Whether you're using a masonry, wood, flat head or countersunk
可曾想过这数以百万计的 坚韧小钉子是如何做到分毫不差的
have you ever wondered how they make millions of these tough little pins to exact dimensions?
几乎所有钉子都以同样的方式开始它们的旅程
Just about all nails start out their journey in the same way.
大多数由高耐久性的碳钢制成
Most are made from highly durable carbon steel.
它们最初以钢丝的形态出现
Which originates in steel wire form.
卷在卷筒上，这卷钢丝重达2000多公斤
Rolled up on a drum, this wire weighs in at over 2,000 kilos.
钢丝直径6毫米，实在太粗了
The wire's diameter is 6mm, which is too large,
因此要通过拉伸工艺减小钢丝直径
so a stretching process reduces the steel's width.
经过多个卷筒反复拉伸，钢丝逐渐变细
Using many drums, the wire is pulled repeatedly to gradually thin it.
随后钢丝被卷绕到卷筒上
It's then rolled onto a drum.
卷满后，这卷钢丝超过23千米，重1136公斤
When full, this roll contains over 23,000 meters of wire, weighing in at 1,136 kilos.
此时钢丝直径已减到2.84毫米
The wire is now a diameter of 2.84mm,
还需再减半一次
so will have to be reduced by half again.
现在钢丝被切割成小段
It's now cut into small rods.
切割好的钢丝段由这台电磁铁吸起
The cut rods are gathered up with this electromagnet
然后送入加工它们的机器
and dumped into a machine that will process them.
接下来是重点：钢段由刀片削出钉尖，变成钉子
Now comes the important bit: the rods are turned into nails by a blade that forms the nail's point.
这台机器用巨大压力压扁钢段末端，制成钉头
This machine forms nail heads by flattening them using great pressure on the rod ends.
钉头以每分钟1400个的速度成型
Nail heads are formed at a rate of 1,400 per minute.
钉子的制造到此完成
The manufacturing of the nails is now finished.
接下来是包装
Next comes the packaging.
这些钉子嵌在塑料卷条里出售
These nails are sold embedded in plastic rolls.
这台机器每卷装入167枚钉子
This machine inserts 167 nails into each roll.
塑料条上有齿，钉子钩在上面
The plastic strip has teeth, and the nails hook into these.
制造螺旋钉需要多一道工序
Making spiral nails requires an extra processing step.
这台机器用这些滚筒给钉子旋出螺旋纹
This machine puts the spiral into the nails with these cylinders.
每分钟产出1200枚
and produces 1,200 nails a minute.
随后钉子被拼成条状，供气动射钉枪使用
Then the nails are put together into strips for use in pneumatic nailing guns.
为了固定，钉子上涂覆树脂，4分钟即可干燥
To keep them in place, the nails are coated with the resin that dries in 4 minutes.
这就是使用条装钉子的射钉装置
This is the nailing device that uses nails on a strip.
只需扣动扳机就能把钉子射出
It strikes the nails with just the pull of a trigger.
这家工厂还生产订书钉
This factory also produces staples.
订书钉压制机将80根铁丝压合在一起
The staple press binds 80 iron wires,
这些铁丝已排列整齐、并排摆放
which have been lined up and placed side by side.
随后铁丝被粘合在一起
The wires are then glued together.
铁丝最终成为一整条粘连的带条
The wires then come out in one adhered strip.
订书钉带条送入这台机器
The staple strips are fed into this machine,
它把订书钉切割成所需长度并折弯
which cuts the staples to the desired length and folds
压机使用40顿压力， 一次冲压完成折弯
them in one stroke of this press, applying 40 tons of pressure.
订书钉在这台模具上成型
Staples are formed on this gauge,
订书钉带条随即进入包装环节
and the staple strips are then ready for packaging.
这家工厂每天总计生产2500万枚钉子和订书钉
Every day, this factory produces a total of 25 million nails and staples.
它们挽救过许多工人和金属工匠的视力
They've saved the sight of many a workman and metalworker.
从壁球运动员到刑侦人员
From squash players to crime scene investigators,
全世界都信赖它们来保护我们的视力
they are trusted the world over to save our vision.
无论你周末想做点手工活
So whether you're doing a spot of DIY this weekend or
还是身处危险环境，你都会想看接下来这个环节
working in a dangerous environment, you'll want to catch. This next segment.
许多运动和行业都需要佩戴护目镜
Many sports and trades require the wearing of safety glasses.
这些眼镜在这样的模具中注塑制成
These glasses are made by shaping plastic in molds such as this.
镜片的光学部分经过精密加工，以保证尽可能透明且不发生变形
The optical part of the lens is mirrored in order to be as transparent as possible without being deformed.
眼镜主要由熔化的树脂制成
The glasses are made by melting the primary material,
这是一种名为聚碳酸酯的塑料树脂
a plastic resin called polycarbonate.
树脂颗粒被倒入这台机器中
The resin granules are poured into this machine and
在250摄氏度的温度下熔化为液态
becomes liquefied at a temperature of 250 degrees centigrade.
液态塑料在压力下注入模具
The liquid plastic is injected into the mold under pressure.
塑料迅速硬化，随后眼镜从模具中取出
The plastic hardens rapidly and the glasses are then removed from the mold.
眼镜被手工分离，并进行初步目检
The glasses are separated by hand and given an initial visual inspection.
护目镜经过清洗，去除杂质，为下一道工序做准备
The goggles are washed to eliminate any impurities and to ready them for the next phase.
它们被送往实验室，接受表面处理涂层
They're taken to the laboratory where they're given a coating of surface treatment.
随后眼镜用清水冲洗
The glasses are then rinsed in clear water.
接着眼镜被缓缓浸入化学溶液中
The glasses are then gently soaked in a chemical solution
这种溶液能防止镜片起雾和刮伤
which prevents misting and scratching of the lens.
涂层现在需要进行固化
This coating now has to be cooked.
眼镜穿过加热到120摄氏度的烘箱
The glasses are passed through an oven heated to 120 degrees centigrade.
浸泡和固化过程长达2小时
The soaking and cooking process can last up to 2 hours.
每副眼镜都要接受检查，以确保镜片上没有瑕疵或变形
Each pair of glasses is inspected to make sure there are no imperfections or distortions in the lenses.
眼镜被固定在支架上，便于车床加工
The glasses are placed on a support, securing it for the lathes.
这台铣床自动去除最后一块聚碳酸酯
This milling machine automatically removes the last piece of polycarbonate.
这块料留下是为了让眼镜能够被拿起而无需触碰镜片
which was left in place so that the glasses could be handled without having to touch the lenses.
随后粘上鼻托
The nose piece is then glued on.
每批产品中都会抽取几副眼镜进行测试
Certain pairs of glasses are selected from each production run.
在这里，他们测试眼镜能否抵挡以140公里时速的撞击的壁球
Here, they evaluate the resistance of the glasses to a squash ball shot at them at 140 kilometers per hour.
这里还用100公里时速的冰球测试曲棍球面罩
Here, a hockey visor is tested against a puck traveling at 100 kilometers per hour.
为符合安全标准，眼镜必须通过这些测试
To conform to safety standards, the glasses must withstand these tests.
证明它们确实安全可靠
It confirms that they're truly safe.
接下来进入护目镜的最后组装工序
They now proceed to final assembly steps in making the glasses.
最后几个部件，如塑料镜腿，被安装上去
The last few pieces, such as the plastic ear stems, are installed.
组装完成后，眼镜被装入包装盒
Now completed, the glasses are placed in cases,
这是制造过程的最后一步
and is the final step in their fabrication.
这家公司生产多种护目镜：
This company makes several types of safety glasses:
工业用、曲棍球和橄榄球面罩
industrial, hockey and football visors,
以及游泳镜和壁球眼镜
swimming goggles, and squash glasses.
这家工厂每天生产数千副护目镜
The facility turns out thousands of safety glasses
制造这些护目镜所用的聚碳酸酯树脂
every day, and the polycarbonate resin used to make these safety
有朝一日或许能保住你的视力
glasses could one day save your sight.
接下来请看《造物小百科》
Coming up on how it's made
布料
fabrics.
工业革命让布料走进千家万户
The Industrial Revolution brought fabric to the masses.
如今，单个纱线筒就能纺出25公里长的布
And today, a single bobbin can produce 25 kilometers of cloth.
自行车：配备多级变速和高科技材料
And bicycles, with multiple gears and high-tech materials,
无论幽静小路还是最崎岖的山地都如履平地
they're made to tackle everything from quiet paths to the most rugged mountain trails.
稍作休息，马上回来
Join us after the break.
欢迎回到《造物小百科》
Welcome back to How It's Made.
稍后，我们将看自行车， 从多级变速到高科技材料
Later, we look at bikes from multiple gears to high-tech materials
从平顺的公路到崎岖的山地
from quiet cycle paths to the most rugged mountain trails.
不过首先，远古人类靠兽皮来抵御风雨
But first, early man relied on animal skins to protect himself against the elements.
后来，布料让人类不再需要为穿衣而捕猎
Eventually, fabrics eliminated the need to hunt for our clothes,
织布机的发明让布料走进千家万户
and the invention of the loom brought cloth to the masses.
如今，纺织厂能织出各种图案和颜色的布料
Today, textile mills make fabrics in every conceivable pattern and color.
布料由成千上万根交织的纱线织成
Fabric is made from thousands of braided threads.
这家工厂有700个涤纶纱线筒
This mill has 700 bobbins of polyester,
每个纱线筒装有25万米纱线
with each bobbin containing 250,000 meters of thread.
这个装置称为经纱装置，汇集700根纤维
This unit, called a warp, takes the 700 fibers, assembles.
再将其梳理成分开的纱束
Then combs them into separate strands.
再不断加入其他纱线，最终共有7000根排列整齐的纱线
Other strands are added until, in total, there are 7,000 aligned threads.
布料由互相成90度交织的纱线组成
The fabric is composed of threads braided at 90 degrees to each other.
经纱沿纵向排列
Then the warp threads are assembled lengthwise,
其他纱线则横向穿过
whilst others are joined diagonally.
为防止纱线断裂，它们要先涂一层胶水
To prevent the threads from tearing, they pass through a bin of glue.
这些滚筒去除多余的胶水
These rollers eliminate the surplus.
染色前胶水会被水洗去
The glue will be removed with water before dyeing the threads.
这些大型绿色滚筒加热并烘干纱线上的胶水
These large green cylinders are heated and dry the glue on the threads.
粘合好的纱束在织机滚筒上被分开
The glued strands are separated on this loom roller.
每根纱线都要穿过综丝，以织出特定花纹
综丝: 中间有一个小孔，叫做综眼。每根综丝控制一根经纱。织布时，综丝上下移动，带动经纱分开，好让纬纱穿过去。
Each thread must pass through a blade to produce a specific design.
这台设备将7000根纱线
This piece of equipment takes the 7,000 strands of thread
逐一穿过综丝，操作极其精确
one by one and passes them through the blade in a highly precise operation.
就这样，织布终于开始了
And so the weaving finally begins.
在织机滚筒上，经纱由气流喷入
On this loom roller, the warp thread is inserted by a jet of air.
织布机将两个各有7000根纱线的织机滚筒合在一起
The weaving machine assembles two loom rollers made of 7,000 strands.
布幅宽达3.65米
The fabric reaches a width of 3.65 meters.
The dark threads are inserted into the weave.
深色纱线被织入布料中
综丝取出一组纱线，以便织入下一组
The blades remove one set of strands to insert the next ones.
布料实现了工业化生产
The fabric is made on an industrial scale.
这个纱线筒竟装有250公里长的纱线
This bobbin contains an amazing 250 kilometers of thread.
织布机满负荷运转时，每分钟完成600次纱线交织
Operating at full tilt, the loom makes 600 thread intersections every minute.
织布工序完成，接下来进入下一道工序
Weaving is now over, and we move onto the next step.
水洗和染色
Washing and dyeing.
在80摄氏度的皂液中
Washing is done in a soapy solution at 80 degrees in a
以每分钟60米的速度连续水洗
continuous manner at a speed of 60 meters of fabric per minute.
布料再放入30摄氏度的清水中漂洗
The fabric is rinsed in clear water at 30 degrees.
接下来是染色
Next, it's onto dyeing.
这是通过喷射染色机完成的
This is done with jets.
将长达12000米的布料放入加入染料的清水中
Up to 12,000 meters of fabric are placed in clean water into which colorants are added.
布料在加热的染液中， 浸泡约6小时
The solution is heated, and the fabric soaks here for about 6 hours.
随后用温水漂洗
Then it will be rinsed in lukewarm water.
布料随后放入料仓
The fabric is then placed in a bin.
这台机器称为开幅机
This machine is called an opener.
它展开并抻平布料，再卷绕到巨大的滚筒上
It unfolds and stretches the material before rolling it up on an immense roller.
现在，这卷布快卷满了
And now, the roll is almost full.
最后一道工序是热定型
The final step is thermo-setting,
高温烘箱将布料烘干
where a high-temperature oven dries the fabric.
温度高达200摄氏度
At temperatures reaching 200 degrees centigrade,
布料在其中运行45秒
the fabric circulates for 45 seconds.
每一卷成品布都重达1500公斤
With each finished roll weighing in at a hefty 1,500 kilos,
装有25公里长的布料
they hold 25 kilometers of fabric.
自行车早已不同于最初的设计
Bicycles have come a long way from the original design.
如今它们配备多级变速
They now feature multiple gears,
以及碳纤维车架、轻如羽毛的金属合金等高科技材料
high-tech materials like carbon fiber frames, and feather-light metal alloys.
它们无论面对安静的自行车道
And they're made to tackle everything from quiet bike
还是最崎岖的山地都应付自如
paths to the most rugged mountain trails.
1790年法国的发明，最早的自行车形似双轮木马，没有踏板和车把
A French invention of 1790, the first bicycle resembled a two-wheeled wooden horse without pedals or handlebars.
1817年，一位德国人给它加上了方向控制
In 1817, a German gave it direction control.
1861年，法国人又在前轮上加装了踏板
The addition of pedals to the front wheels came from France in 1861.
1870年，英国人加上了硕大的前轮
The large front wheel was added by the British in 1870.
到1903年，著名的环法自行车赛开赛
And by 1903, the famed Tour de France began.
自行车是一件精美的机械杰作
A bicycle is a beautiful piece of engineering.
车架由钢或铬钼钢制成
The frames are made of steel or chromoly.
制造从这些中空钢管开始
Fabrication begins with these hollow tubes.
切管机将钢管切断，再送往弯管机
The tube cutter slices the steel before sending it to the bender.
弯管机对钢管进行冷弯
The bender curves the tubes cold,
以强大压力压向弯管模具
exerting strong pressure against the bending jig.
钢管接下来要进行加工，按长度切割
The tubes must now be machined and are cut into lengths
以便彼此正确套接
so they can correctly fit into one another.
加工过程中，润滑液为钢管降温
During this operation, lubricants cool the tube.
切割时会考虑其他部件的插接角度
The tube is cut, taking into consideration the insertion angle of the other pieces.
需要焊接在一起的钢管被放入这个支架
Tubes to be welded together are placed in this support.
加入银和青铜以增强强度、提高焊接质量
Silver and bronze is added to increase strength and produce a better weld.
车架焊接约需2分钟，温度高达800摄氏度
Welding of the frame requires about 2 minutes at a temperature of 800 degrees centigrade.
焊好后，部件需4分钟冷却
Once welded, the part takes 4 minutes to cool.
构成自行车的其余钢管也已加工完成
The rest of the tubes that go to make up the bike are completed.
此时必须校正车架，因为焊接时车架可能发生变形
At this stage, it's important to straighten the frame which may have deformed during welding.
检查各钢管的对位情况
The alignment of the tubes are verified
然后用工具进行冷校直，使其尺寸准确
and then straightened out cold with a tool that sets it to the right dimensions.
接下来是喷漆工序
Next comes the paint job.
用喷枪喷漆，漆料借助静电吸附在车架上
Paint is applied with a spray gun and adheres to the frame by static contact.
随后漆面在天然气烘箱中以218摄氏度烘烤15分钟
Then the paint will be baked in a natural gas oven at 218 degrees for 15 minutes.
车架冷却后即可开始组装
The frame is now cooled and the assembly can begin.
贴上品牌标牌
The labels are applied.
在工厂另一区域，车把正在组装
In a different part of the factory, the handlebars are assembled.
刹车和变速机构被安装上去
The mechanism for the brakes and the gears are installed.
接下来是轮圈
Next comes the wheel rims.
每个铝制车轮的36根不锈钢辐条均由手工安装
The 36 stainless steel spokes of each aluminium wheel are installed manually.
这些工人的巧手让他们每小时能为65个轮圈装上辐条
The dexterity of these workers allows them to install spokes on 65 wheel rims every hour.
这把辐条工具让他们能把辐条旋入轮圈
This spoke tool allows them to screw the spokes into the rim.
这台机器对辐条施加压力，以达到所需的张紧度
This machine exerts a pressure on the spokes in order to achieve the desired tension.
张力过大或不足，轮圈都会变形
If there is too much or not enough tension, the rim will be crooked.
这台机器负责校正轮圈
This machine aligns the rims.
它自动调节辐条，使车轮完全笔直
It automatically adjusts the spokes so that the wheel will be truly straight.
接下来把内胎和外胎装到轮圈上
Now for the placing of the inner tubes and the tires on the wheel rims.
自行车被倒置，从一个车间传送到另一个车间
Set upside down, the bicycle circulates from one workshop to another,
在这里安装最后的机械部件：
where they will install the last mechanical parts:
车把、脚踏、前叉、刹车以及链条机构，全部由手工安装
the handlebars, pedals, forks, brakes, and chain mechanisms are all installed manually.
这里他们旋上后刹车座
Here they screw on the rear brake plate.
最后，他们检查每一辆自行车，确保螺栓
Finally, they inspect each bicycle to make sure that the bolts
拧紧到位，各部件运转正常
are well tightened and that everything's working properly.
随后进入包装环节
Then, it's onto packaging.
这家工厂每天生产2500辆自行车
This factory makes 2,500 bicycles every day.
每辆重11.4公斤，可骑行数千公里
Each one weighs 11.4 kilos and will run for thousands of kilometers.